Guide to the Gail and Stephen Rudin literary autograph collection, 1841-1993.
Rudin, Gail and Stephen autograph collection, 1841-1993
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Gail and Stephen Rudin literary autograph collection, 1823-1995.
4690
227 items.
Correspondence
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Letters by noted authors, many on the subject of writing. Authors represented include: Louisa May Alcott, James Baldwin, Paul Bowles, Pearl Buck, Raymond Chandler, Agatha Christie, Samuel Clemens, Joseph Conrad, Charles Dickens, Arthur Conan Doyle, Theodore Dreiser, T.S. Eliot, William Faulkner, Robert Frost, Zane Grey, Alex Haley, Nathaniel Hawthorne, Ernest Hemingway, Sinclair Lewis, Jack London, Thomas Mann, Henry Miller, Margaret Mitchell, Vladimir Nabokov, Ezra Pound, Rod Serling, G.B. Shaw, John Steinbeck, William M. Thackeray, Kurt Vonnegut, H.G. Wells, E.B. White, and William Wordsworth.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Letters by noted authors, many on the subject of writing. Authors represented include: Louisa May Alcott, James Baldwin, Paul Bowles, Pearl Buck, Raymond Chandler, Agatha Christie, Samuel Clemens, Joseph Conrad, Charles Dickens, Arthur Conan Doyle, Theodore Dreiser, T.S. Eliot, William Faulkner, Robert Frost, Zane Grey, Alex Haley, Nathaniel Hawthorne, Ernest Hemingway, Sinclair Lewis, Jack London, Thomas Mann, Henry Miller, Margaret Mitchell, Vladimir Nabokov, Ezra Pound, Rod Serling, G.B. Shaw, John Steinbeck, William M. Thackeray, Kurt Vonnegut, H.G. Wells, E.B. White, and William Wordsworth. Also an additional gathering of letters by famous literary figures.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Alcott, Louisa May, 1832-1888.; Baldwin, James, 1924-; Bowles, Paul, 1910-; Buck, Pearl S.(Pearl Sydenstricker), 1892-1973.; Chandler, Raymond, 1888-1959.; Christie, Agatha, 1890-1976.; Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910.; Conrad, Joseph, 1857-1924.; Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870.; Doyle, Arthur Conan, 1859-1930.; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945.; Eliot, T. S.(Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965.; Faulkner, William, 1897-1962.; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963.; Grey, Zane, 1872-1939.; Haley, Alex.; Hawthorne, Nathaniel, 1804-1864.; Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961.; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951.; London, Jack, 1876-1916.; Mann, Thomas, 1875-1955.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980.; Mitchell, Margaret, 1900-1949.; Nabokov, Vladimir Vladimirovich, 1899-1977.; Pound, Ezra, 1885-1972.; Serling, Rod, 1924-; Shaw, Bernard, 1856-1950.; Steinbeck, John, 1902-1968.; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863.; Vonnegut, Kurt.; Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946.; White, E. B. (Elwyn Brooks), 1899-; Wordsworth, William, 1770-1850
Subjects:
Authorship.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Albee, Edward: Typed letter to Mr. Allen. Lexington, VA., May 22, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Regarding drama critics.
- Alcott, Louisa May: Autograph letter to Mr. Wendell Phillips., Feb. 10, no year (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ambler, Eric: signed letter to John Davenport, Esq.. APO 512, Nov. 15, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Ambler bemoans his intellectually deprived situation (in the Army), "Nobody here reads anything but The Stars and Stripes…"
  Rudin # B-1
- Ambler, Eric: Typed letter to Donald McCormick, Esq.. Los Angeles CA, Aug. 19, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Discusses the inspiration behind his book, The Mask of Dimitrios.
  Rudin # B-2
- Anderson, Jack: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. New York, NY., Jul. 15, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 2A)
- Anderson, Maxwell: signed letter to Mr. Benson. Stamford, CT, Feb. 9, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Anderson sternly lectures a young writer and tells of his own writing history.
  Rudin # B-3
- Anderson, Sherwood: signed letter to Frederick O'Brien., ca. 1920s (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Anderson dispenses advice to O'Brien about writing.
  Rudin # B-4
- Anderson, Sherwood: Autograph letter to Lois Wright., Jan. 2, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Regarding personal life.
- Anderson, Sherwood: Autographed letter to Frederick Harrold. New York, NY., Dec. 21, c. 1923 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  In answer to a complimentary letter from a fan. In a presentation portfolio.
  Rudin # B-5A
- Anderson, Sherwood: Typed letter to Publicity Department- Boni and Liveright. New Orleans, LA, Mar. 29, 1926? (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Letter to his publisher offering an autobiographical sketch of himself.
  Rudin # B-5
- Anderson, Sherwood: Typed letter to Miss Frieda Meredith Dietz. Marion, VA., Jul. 28, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Regarding Southern Literary Messenger.
- Asimov, Isaac: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. West Newton, MA., Aug. 24, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Regarding education and writing.
- Asimov, Isaac: Signed postcard to Sean A. Hicks. New York, NY., May 12, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Regarding desire to write.
- Asimov, Isaac: Typed letter to Reverend William Ward. New York, NY., Jul. 24, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  Letter to a clergyman who wants to read all of his books. He informs him that he has written 327 of them!
  Rudin # B-6
- Atherton, Gertrude: Typed letter to AD Wright. San Francisco, CA., Aug. 29, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  Atherton discusses her work and her position on women's rights. Located in a presentation portfolio.
  Rudin # B-6A
- Auden, Wystan: Autograph letter to Harvey Breit. Napoli, Italy., May 30, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Regarding dislike of being photographed, personal views on writing.
- Baldwin, James: Typed letter to Samuel L. Blumenfield. Paris, France., Oct. 29, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  Baldwin complains that he doesn't think his book was properly advertised; he is in the process of finishing a play; and he indicates that he isn't drinking any more than normal.
  Rudin # B-7
- Baldwin, James: Typed letter to Samuel L. Blumenfield. Paris, France., Oct. 8, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  Baldwin discusses the theme and characters of his new book "Giovanni's Room" and fears censorship by his publishers - Included is a first edition of the book. (Book is catalogued individually).
  Rudin # B-8
- Baldwin, James: Signed card., No date (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Regarding struggle vs. satisfaction.
- Barker, A.L.: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley., Aug. 8, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8A)
- Barrie, James: Signed letter to Nicholas Murray Butler. The Athenaeum S.W., Jan. 23, 1919 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  "Dear Brutus" is an allegory.
  Rudin # B-9
- Belitt, Ben: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Bennington VT., Mar. 29, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9A)
- Bell, Clive: Signed letter to Wesley Hartley. Charleston, Firle, Sussex., Oct. 26, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  Gives his opinions on education and schools.
  Rudin # B-10
- Bell, E.T.: Autograph letter to Wesley Hartley. Pasadena, CA., May 13, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bellow, Saul: Typed letter to Samuel Goldberg., Dec. 13, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  He writes of his divorce, his inability to think in NY and the publication of his novelette.
  Rudin # B-11
- Bellow, Saul: Autographed letter. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  Working draft of his 1976 Nobel Prize acceptance speech; included are instructions from Svenska Handelsbanken on how to obtain his prize money.
  Rudin # B-12
- Bemelmans, Ludwig: Typed letter to Mr. Hartley. Paris, France., Aug. 2, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Comparing being a writer to having a disease.
- Benchley, Robert: Typed letter to Dearest Mother. Hollywood, CA., Dec. 7, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  Benchley writes of the weather, what he is working on in CA and what his future plans will be.
  Rudin # B-13
- Benet, William Rose: Typed letter to Mr. Harlan Umansky. New York, NY., Nov. 20, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Regarding rejection of aspiring poet Umansky.
- Benson, E.F.: Letters to Miss Carey. Norfolk, Rye, London., Aug. 13, 1922-Dec. 3, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  Group of four letters plus manuscript responding to a request to read and comment on short story submissions.
  Rudin # B-13A
- Bentley, Phyllis: Typed letters to Wesley Hartley. Halifax., 1958, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 14A)
- Betjeman, John: Typed letter to "Assistant Secretary". Berkshire., Jul. 23, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Regarding experience with periodicals.
- Bierce, Ambrose: Autograph letter to Lella Cotton. Washington D.C., Apr. 14, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Regarding death of Lella's father.
- Bierce, Ambrose: Typed letter to Walter Neale. Washington, DC., Jan. 8, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  He responds to his publisher regarding the typographical errors in the final printed version of the recently published "Collected Works".
  Rudin # B-14
- Bishop, Morris: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Ithaca, NY., Dec. 3, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 15A)
- Blackmur, R.P.: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Princeton, NJ., Oct. 29, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 15B)
- Borges, Jorge Luis: Typed letter to John Norbutt. Buenos Aires, Argentina., Jun. 27, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  Borges tells how to write work of "lasting importance".
  Rudin # B-15
- Bottome, Phyllis: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley., Nov. 25, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 16A)
- Boucher, Anthony: Typed letter to Mr. Hartley., Oct. 30, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Bowles, Paul: Typed letter to Mr. Vance Morgan. Tangier, Morocco., Feb. 18, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Regarding a turning point in his literary life.
- Bradbury, Ray: Typed letter to Nard. Los Abgeles 64, CA. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  "I don't have to discover [Christ] anew, since He discovered me, a long while back."
  Rudin # B-16
- Bradbury, Ray: Typed letter to Sean Hicks. Los Angeles, CA., Jul. 17, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Bretnor, Reginald: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Berkeley, CA., Oct. 25, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Bridge, Ann (Kate Willert): Two autographed letters to Wesley Hartley., 1958, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 17A)
- Bryant, William Cullen: Autograph letter to Earl Marble. Long Island, NY., May 16, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Regarding biographical information.
- Buchwald, Art: Typed Manuscript. New School, NYC., Jun. 14, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  Regarding a panel discussion of Jewish Humor.
  Rudin # B-17
- Buck, Pearl S.: Autographed letter to John Walsh., Nov. 11, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  Buck writes to her publisher and future husband asking his advice about receiving an honorary degree and about speaking to a negro women's group.
  Rudin # B-19
- Buck, Pearl: Typed manuscript., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  On the Writing of Novels.
- Buck, Pearl S.: Typed letter to Miss Tremaine. New York, NY., Jan. 21, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  "I must say the fact remains that China needs reassurance of our friendship and needs it now." Letter on political relations.
  Rudin # B-20
- Buck, Pearl S.: Typed letter to Mrs. Cheyney. Perkasie, PA., Dec. 19, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  Buck sends a Chinese poem followed by politically charged paragraphs about the Chinese, revolution and Communism.
  Rudin # B-21
- Buck, Pearl S.: Typed manuscript with corrections., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  "My World of Home": A memoir and reflections relating to Buck's childhood in China.
  Rudin # B-21a
- Buck, Pearl S.: Typed letter to Mr. Jerry Granat. Perkasie, PA., Apr. 7, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  She writes regarding the differences in Asian people of different countries.
  Rudin # B-22
- Buck, Pearl S.: Typed manuscript., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  Two drafts of the story "Miracle Child" originally published in the December 1973 issue of "Good Housekeeping".
  Rudin # B-23
- Buck, Pearl S.: Autographed manuscript., Feb. 18, 1925
  Extensive critique of Joseph Conrad's "Victory" - written inside his book from her library. (Book is catalogued individually)
- Burroughs, Edgar Rice: Typed letter to Mr. Ralph J. Saterlee. Tarzana, CA., Oct. 10, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Burroughs, John: Autographed manuscript., 1906 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  The original manuscript of Burroughs' essay on the evil effect of extravagant toys upon children.
  Rudin # B-24
- Burroughs, William S.: Typed letter to Mr. Nargi. Lawrence, KS. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  "I do not feel that [Samuel Beckett] has had a specific influence on my own work…I doubt very much if my example has influenced Beckett".
  Rudin # B-25
- Burt, Struthers: Autograph letter to Professor Munson. Southern Pines, NC., Apr. 22, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Regarding Burt's personal writing process, Festive.
- Bynner, Witter: Typed letters to Wesley Hartley. Santa Fe, NM., Nov. 27, 1957; Dec. 9, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Caldwell, Erskine: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. San Francisco, CA., Jul. 21, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Caldwell, Taylor: Typed letter to editor of Look magazine. Buffalo, NY., Jan. 9, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Regarding prediction of future by Look.
- Campbell, John: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. New York, NY., Sep. 28, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Capote, Truman: Typed letter to Mr. William Shawn. New York, NY., Oct. 5, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Regarding permanent leave to Switzerland. With photo.
- Carlyle, Thomas: Signed letter to James Hannay. Chelsea., Oct. 4, 1849 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  Discusses "Literature as a practical employment".
  Rudin # B-26
- Cather, Willa: signed letters to Emmy Liddell., 1943-1946 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Cather writes with disdain reflecting her feelings towards Hollywood and celebrity culture. Also included are two handwritten letters of admiration dated 5/9/1943 and 5/27/1946 from Liddell to Cather.
  Rudin # B-26A
- Catton, Bruce: Typed letter to Mr. Fulton. New York, NY., Mar. 7, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Regarding war and peace.
- Chandler, Raymond: Typed letter to Mr. H.N. Swanson. La Jolla, CA., Dec. 16, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Regarding The Pocket Atlantic.
- Chandler, Raymond: Typed letter to Angello Hampares. La Jolla, CA., Jul. 28, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  A letter to an aspiring mystery writer offering advice.
  Rudin # B-27
- Chandler, Raymond: Typed letter to H.N. Swanson. La Jolla, CA., Jan. 2, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  Thanks his agent for the gift of a tie. Discusses the coordination of radio and television contracts.
  Rudin # B-28
- Chandler, Raymond: Typed letter to William Gault. La Jolla, CA., Apr. 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Regarding mystery genre.
- Chandler, Raymond: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. La Jolla, CA., Dec. 3, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  Discusses whether a college education is necessary for creative writing. "What is necessary to creative writing is a creative mind."
  Rudin # B-28A
- Chappell, Fred: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Laconia, NH., May 23, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 29A)
- Cheever, John: Two typed letters to Jerry Granat, Apr. 19, 24, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  Two letters, one stating that he never took a course in writing, the other mentioning some "splendid courses in writing" and also mentioning his father's correspondence with the King.
  Rudin # B-29
- Chesterton, GK: Typescript. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  Typescript and page proofs of his article "This Unpsychological Age", attacking his generation's addiction to hedonism.
  Rudin # B-30
- Christie, Agatha: Typed letter to John Ewing. Berkshire., Jan. 31, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  Denial that her novels are anti-Semitic. Signed "Agatha Mallowan".
- Christie, Agatha: Autograph letter to Anthony Shaffe. Churston Ferrers, South Devon., Jul. 8, c. 1940s (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Regarding manuscripts.
- Ciardi, John: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Metuchen, NJ., Jul. 18, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 30A)
- Clarke, Arthur C.: Typed letter to Sean Hicks. Sri Lanka., Feb. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Regarding space, advice, authors.
- Clemens, Samuel: Autograph letter to Jack. Hartford, CT., Jun. 23, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  With 2 photographs, Samuel Clemens postage stamps.
- Clemens, Samuel L: ALS, November 30, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 33a)
  On his 65th birthday, Twain admits his softness for some impish neighborhood boys who congregate on his front steps.
  Rudin # B-30A
- Clemens, Samuel: Autograph letter to Clara Clemens. New York, NY., Mar. 5, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Personal letter to his daughter.
- Coit, Margaret Louise: Autographed letter to Wesley Hartley. NJ., 1957 (Box 7, Folder 30B)
- Conrad, Joseph: Letter to Mr. Hughes. Bishopsbourne, Kent., Sep. 2, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Response to letter from Hughes.
- Cooper, James Fenimore: Autograph letter to Henry Carey., 1836? (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Recommendation of an author.
- Coward, Noel: Autograph letter to T.E. Lawrence. London., Aug. 25, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Regarding The Mint.
- Cowley, Malcolm: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Sherman, CT., Aug. 5, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 30C)
- Cronin, AJ: Autographed letter to Alan. Switzerland., Mar. 25, 1976. (Box 7, Folder 31)
  On becoming an author.
  Rudin # B-31
- Cummings, E.E.: Typed letter to Sanders Russell. NH., Aug. 2, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  Discusses the role of a critic and how it affects the writer.
  Rudin # B-32
- Cummings, E.E.: Typed letter to Seymour. New York, NY., Dec. 4, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Regarding publishing of nonlectures.
- de Camp, L. Sprague: Typed letter to Mr. Hartley. Wallingford, PA., Aug. 27, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- De Quincey, Thomas: Autograph letter to J.A. Hessy. Kendal., Dec. 6, 1823 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Regarding Hessy's opium addiction.
- Dickens, Charles: Autograph letter to Dr. Thomas Southwood Smith. London, England., Dec. 15, 1840 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  Dickens writing on child labour in early Victorian Britain.
  Rudin # B-33
- Dickens, Charles: Typed letter to Madam. Boston, MA., Feb. 2, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Regarding dinner given to Dickens.
- Dickens, Charles: Autograph letter to Sir. London., Sep. 6, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Regarding Child's History of England.
- Dickey, James: Typed letter, signed photograph to Leon Moritz. Columbia, SC., Aug. 8, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  Provides advice on creative writing.
  Rudin # B-34
- Dodgson, Charles L.: Photo (Box 7, Folder 34a)
  Photograph of Xie Kitchin seated on a sofa in a dark dress.
  Rudin # B-34A
- Dodgson, Charles L.: ALS to Xie Kitchin, April 23, 1876 (Box 7, Folder 34a)
  "Why doesn't she write?" Signed "Lewis Carroll".
  Rudin # B-34B
- Dodgson, Charles L.: ALS to Mrs. Kitchin, May 31, 1880 (Box 7, Folder 34a)
  Letter describing his photography.
  Rudin # B-34C
- Doyle, Arthur Conan: Two autograph letters to Margaret Ryan/Mam, ca. 1889 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Letter of condolence; Regarding new literary career
- Doyle, Arthur Conan: ALS, April 29, 1927 or 1928 (Box 1, Folder 43a)
  "I was glad to withdraw Holmes before the public were too weary of him".
  Rudin # B-35
- Doyle, Arthur Conan: Typed letter to Lippincott's Magazine. Bush Villa, Southsea., Oct. 1, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Regarding two stories for publishing by Lippincott's.
- Dreiser, Theodore: Autograph letter to Sister Carrie (sister Claire). New York, NY., Apr. 13, 1895 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Regarding death of sister's infant child.
- Dreiser, Theodore: Autograph letter to Ellen Holst. New York, NY., Jan. 9, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Regarding Sister Carrie.
- Du Maurier, Daphne: Two typed letters to Webb Sullivan. Menabilly Par Cornwall., Jul. 15, 28, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  Two letters - Talks of how she wrote the story of "Rebecca" and offers corrected facts on her background.
- Du Maurier, Daphne: Typed letter to Mr. Heppner. Menabilly Par Cornwall., Jul. 14, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  "None of my novels were ever turned down by publishers!"
  Rudin # B-36
- Du Maurier, Daphne: Ten typed letters, 3 cards with photos, 2 telegrams to Fanny Holtzmann, September Tide., Sep. 30, 1952 - Jan. 1, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Durrell, Lawrence: Typed letter to Madame Pirkko-Lisa Stahl., Aug. 8, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  An insight into his literary tastes while commenting on the Nobel Prize for Literature.
  Rudin # B-37
- Eliot, T.S.: Typed letter to Madame Else Gress. London., Oct. 30, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Regarding Johannes Jorgensen's 80th birthday.
- Eliot, T.S.: Typed letter to Mr. Dale Fern. London., Mar. 20, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Regarding a festival of Eliot's work, The Family Reunion.
- Eliot, T.S.: Typed letter to Rufus Alexander. London., Jan. 9, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  Offering criticism of a submitted poem.
  Rudin # B-38
- Ellis, Havelock: Typed article., c. 1930 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Crime and its Remedies.
- Ellis, Havelock: Two autographed letters. One to Richard Smith, one to Gerald Jones., Jul. 18, 1932 and Mar. 12, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  Two letters - In the first letter Ellis doesn't think the title of his book "Psychology of Sex" should be altered; in the second letter he joins in a petition on behalf of his late friend.
  Rudin # B-39
- Emerson, Ralph Waldo: Autograph letter to Cyrus Bartol. Concord, MA., Sep. 16, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  With printed leaflet.
- Empson, Sir William: Autographed letter to Wesley Hartley. Sheffield University., Mar. 12, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 7A)
- Farrell, James: Typed letter to George S. Daniels. New York, NY., May 19, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Regarding characters and environments in writing, education.
- Farrell, James T.: Autographed letter to Gilbert D. Gibson. New York., Feb. 26, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  A long letter about refusing to send a signed photo, about being a writer, and about some of the grievances he feels against the commercial world.
  Rudin # B-40
- Farrell, James T.: Autographed letter to Charles A. Pearce. New York., Feb. 10, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  A letter to his editor at Harcourt Brace discussing his writing and his lectures.
  Rudin # B-41
- Faulkner, William: Typed letter to Robert Ballou. Oxford, MA., Apr. 25, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Regarding movie deal for Sanctuary.
- Faulkner, William: Typed letter to Paramount Publix Corporation., Jun. 16, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Contract between Faulkner and Paramount.
- Ferber, Edna: Typed letter to Bernard Sobel. 50 Central Park West, NY, Jan. 25, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  Ferber writes that the wedding in "Show Boat" is the actual story of people she has met.
  Rudin # B-42
- Ferber, Edna: Two diaries., 1930 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  Lot of two pocket diaries for the year 1930.
  Rudin # B-43
- Ferber, Edna: Typed letter to Maurice Schwartz. New York, NY., Apr. 2, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Regarding Yoshe Kalb.
- Ferber, Edna: Typed letter to Fannie., Sep. 21, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  She gives her sister a stern lecture about their elderly and fatally ill mother.
  Rudin # B-44
- Ferril, Thomas Hornsby: Typed letter to Wesley Hartley. Denver, CO., Aug. 2, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 8A)
- Fisher, Vardis Alvero: Typed letter to Mr. Warren. Salt Lake City, UT., Jun. 4, 1928 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  Writes of when he started writing, his future, and what it takes to be a writer.
  Rudin # B-45
- Fitzgerald, F. Scott: Autographed letter to Mr. Leach. Paris, France., ca. 1925 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  Outlines his fee schedule for writing short stories. "I have to write popular short stories in order to get money to write what I want to do - which is novels".
  Rudin # B-45A
- Fitzgerald, F. Scott: Typed letter to Mrs. H.H. Prouse, July 18, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 10B)
  Discusses the history of the Key family.
  Rudin # B-45B
- Fitzgerald, Robert :Autographed letter to Wesley Hartley. Italy., May 10, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 10A)
- Ford, Ford Madox (Hueffer): Autographed letter to Mr. Cobden-Sanderson. London, England., Jan. 5, 1919 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  Writes in search of a publisher that will work with him.
  Rudin # B-46
- Forester, C.S.: Typed letter to Miss Beamish. London., Dec. 26, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Regarding plain-spoken details and subtleties in writing.
- Forester, C.S.: Three typed letters to various addressees. Berkeley, CA., 1945-1948 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  Three typed letters referring to the "Hornblower" series, with additional clippings and carbons.
  Rudin # B-47
- Fowlie, Wallace: Two letters to Wesley Hartley. NC., 1974, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 12A)
- Frankenberg, Lloyd: Autographed letter to Wesley Hartley., Mar. 14, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 12B)